hi everybody welcome back to the channel
today we're going to turn these starbo
salted roasted pistachios into a gelato
I don't have many of them so we're going
to do it in the Ninja
creamy yeah so I got these from uh a
dollar store it wasn't Dollar Tree
whatever it was who cares um these are
salted roasted pistachios and used my
ice cream calculator to add them in
independently these ones have got for 40
g 18 G of fat 2 G saturated fat 11 G of
carbs of which is 4 G of fiber 3 G is
sugar 8 g of protein 170 mg of sodium
and then a little bit of other
stuff so they're just pistachio nuts
with salt added that that's it but they
are in their shells so first thing we
need to do is get
these out of the shells and into the
bowl I'll skip through this
bit right buy pistachios from uh you
know a cheaper Outlet like a dollar
store or something you got to put some
work into them that took about 20
minutes to do
275 G packs um they could have done
really with a little bit more roasting
to get rid of some of this skin but you
know it's not too bad I've seen worse so
we need to weigh these so we know how
much actual
pistachio we
have 76 G there we go so
50% so we bought 2 75 G
packs and we got we got 75
G of actual pistachios so we know we got
75 G worth of our shelled salted
pistachio roasted salted pistachios so
what else you going to need so for the
ninja creamy real pistachio gelato you
are going to need 75 G of your shelled
salted pistachio nuts you're going to
need
358 G of 2ent milk you're going to need
90 g of sugar 5 G of invert sugar so
corn syrup or golden syrup or glucose
syrup anything like
that and 20 G of skim milk powder also
called zero fat milk powder also called
lowfat milk powder that is what you're
going to need so let's get everything
ready and we'll come back right so we've
got our little mini blender here this is
just a um little KitchenAid desktop
thing what we need to do
is weird mark on the side what we need
to do is is to turn these pistachios
into a paste and what most websites tell
you to do is to put things like these
into a food processor and just keep
blitzing it up a you're going to
overheat your machine by doing that and
B it's still not going to be super
smooth so what we need to do is we need
to do this in a slightly roundabout
asout face
way and that is going against the grain
everyone says don't do this because it
100% does work they just don't know how
to do it so we're going to take our
pistachios we're going to put them in
our little blender like
so and this is our sugar and our skin
milk powder we're going to
take you know half a tablespoon of our
sugar and put that in there and what
we're going to do is
start to Blitz this up just for a couple
of minutes cuz what we're going to do
then is add some of
this this is the stage we need to
something a little bit different so what
we're going to do is we're going to get
a mug and we're going to
take just a quarter of that it doesn't I
how much is that it's probably like 100
Mill or so of milk we're going to warm
this in the microwave until it's just
hot enough to touch because what we're
now going to do is we're going to make
sure that our
pistachio sticky powder is off the side
and we're going to start spooning some
of this hot milk into here
and what this does is enables this to
turn into a liquid so we've got a really
nice
thin
pistachio liquid here really really good
now there's two things you can do you
can put all this in a pan and bring it
up to a temperature to make sure your
milk powder is dissolved and your
sugar's dissolved or you can do what I'm
going to do
here I'm going to put all of
that into our
milk and we're going to pop this in the
microwave to warm this up we're not
using a hot processed stabilizer I'm
going to use G gum in a
second so really what we're doing is
we're looking to dissolve our milk
powder and our sugar in the microwave
let's get our guag gum
[Applause]
we don't need a lot so what we're going
to do is we're going to take one scant
teaspoon of sugar and 1/4 teaspoon of
our gu gum just blend those up make sure
there's no
lumps
that and here we have our warmed
milk it's not hot it's just warmed we've
just dissolve that Sugar dissolve the
milk powder we're going to add in our gu
gum with that one teaspoon of sugar into
there get that stirred in
nicely the final ingredient is one
teaspoon of corn syrup don't be afraid
of corn
syrup there's nothing wrong with it at
all the high fructose corn syrup is a
different thing as our milk is warm we
can just stir that in it will blend in
nicely finally all we need to do is to
get our
pistachio paste in here like
this make sure to get it all in there
cuz this recipe does
need that amount 75
G pistachios are really high in
fat and that is what is giving us our
gelato levels of fat in this recipe you
could probably do this with
walnuts cuz they're a high fat nut I
mean a a lot of nuts have a good amount
of fat in them but there we go that's
all in there we're going to
just wish that
together
delicious and there is our pistachio
gelato ice cream
base taste good already can smell
it what we're going to do take our ninja
creamy
tub in the world's worst pouring jug
let's go
fast there we go
in the freezer that goes now there's
solids in here there's the nut solids if
you just put this in the freezer those
nut solids are going to sink to the
bottom of this tub we don't want that
periodically during the freezing process
take a whisk spoon a fork whatever you
got and just stir it back up we don't
want to let this settle all right so
let's get this in the freezer and then
we'll come back when it's
done all right completely Frozen it's
been a couple of days
let's get
this in the
machine God that thing takes forever I
put this on gelato setting just
cuz well why not but I just wonder why
it takes so bloody
long
to lift the uh blade up
anyway let's don't want to waste any of
this let's get some dished up see how
this turned
[Music]
out smells delicious texture looks
excellent super smooth
dense Ultra pistachio kind of flavor
going on in here
man this is delicious yeah incredible
the ninja creamy really
benefits a kind of thick dense fudgy ice
cream and or
gelatin without the overun it it can
benefit some flavors more than others
chocolate benefits from it because it's
a luxurious kind of mouth feel the
pistachio is quite a light
flavor so it really benefits having that
thick dense texture
yeah winner
so couple of notes if you're buying
shell uh if you're buying pistachios in
their shell then by the time you process
them to use you're going to cut your
weight down in
half so I started with 150 g of
pistachios in their shell these are
salted pistachios that it's
important by the time I removed all the
shells I was left with 75 G of usable
nut um good quality don't worry about
like the per little bits of
purple papery skin over some of them it
it's not a problem that that's something
that benefits the ninja creamy it gets
decimated in the in this
spin but this is really really nice I
haven't made pistachio for a long time
and the last time I made it on this
channel it was a plant-based using a
really special
UK plant-based cream which can't get of
here super easy one to make you don't
need all the crazy stuff the stabilizer
really does help even if you just use gu
gum or something and that method here is
just super quick and easy don't even
have to cook it just use your microwave
anyway thanks very much for watching
don't forget to like And subscribe I am
doing
matcha next
week then something to do a coffee in
the Ninja creamy the week after so if
you don't want to miss those hit that
subscribe button like comment do all the
other and I will see you next time
[Music]